HAMZAT HABIBLLAHI ADEWALE

Plot 6/8 Araromi Igbehinadun Community, Road 1, Ajofeebo, Sanyo Area, Ibadan, Oyo State, Nigeria https://www.linkedin.com/in/hamzat-habibllahi-8b9542110

bitlylink.com/habibllahi habibllahi3@gmail.com +234[0]8142408496

ACADEMIC QUALIFICATIONS

FEDERAL UNIVERSITY OF AGRICULTURE ABEOKUTA (FUNAAB)

2015

Bachelor of Engineering (Electrical and Electronics Engineering); second class upper.

OLADIPO ALAYANDE SCHOOL OF SCIENCE

2009

West Africa Senior School Certificate.

SKILLS

Back-end Language

Java, Kotlin

Frameworks

Spring, JUnit, Hibernate, Mockito

Integrated Development Environments (IDEs)

Android Studio

Intellij IDEA

NetBeans IDE

Application programming interface (API)

Android API

JavaFX API

Software area of specialization:

Desktop solution development,

Android solution development

Others

- 1) Electrical installation (conduit and surface).
- 2) Solar hybrid installation.

PRESENTATIONS

Presentation: DESIGN OF INDUSTRIAL BASED TEMPERATURE AND HUMIDITY MONITORING SYSTEM USING EMBEDDED SYSTEM APPROACH FOR HEALTH AND SAFETY.

The Nigerian Universities Engineering Students' Association (NUESA) Conference. 2015. Nigeria.

HONOUR AND AWARD

BEST INTELLECT AND PRODUCTIVITY

2015

The Nigerian Universities Engineering Students' Association (NUESA) FUNAAB chapter College of Engineering FUNAAB

COMMUNITY SERVICES

National Youth Service Corp (NYSC) teacher

2016 - 2017

Abonnema Girls School, Abonnema, Rivers state, Nigeria

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

Code Trik Nigeria Enterprises

2019-Recent

Software developer

Responsibilities:

Development of android mobile and desktop software solutions

Freelance 2018 – 2019

Software developer

Responsibilities:

Development of android mobile and desktop software solutions

HIC mikroLAB, Ogun state, Nigeria

2017 - 2018

Embedded system developer

Responsibilities:

- 1) Design, development and simulation of analogue, digital and embedded system as a control solution.
- 2) Installation of a solar hybrid system as a sustainable and renewable electrical energy source for clients.
- 3) Fundamental electronics trainer.

HIC mikroLAB, Ogun state, Nigeria

2014-2015

Industrial attachment trainee.

Responsibility:

To technically participate in all indoor and outdoor works as a trainee.

CAREER OBJECTIVES

To be the best Java | Kotlin programmer and tutor in Nigeria. Developing great business and control Android mobile and cross-platform desktop solutions.

ABOUT

I am a software developer whose interest and practice lies in cross-platform desktop solution development and android mobile solution development. I also have embedded system development experience using AVR microcontrollers.

I like to develop an interactive desktop/android mobile solutions that makes monitoring and control of an electrical system easy and seamless via customized developed embedded system. Outside control, I like to develop custom and business desktop/android solutions. I prefer programming with Java and Kotlin because both languages are JVM type, 100% interoperable with one another and are both powerful languages for android and desktop solution development.

Am not just a code geek, I do solar and electrical installations of various capacities for residential and commercial consumers.

PERSONAL DETAILS

Date of birth: 29th January 1992, Nationality: Nigerian, State of Origin: Ogun State

Local Government Area: Abeokuta-South, Sex: Male

HOBBIES AND LEISURE INTERESTS

- Watching technological audio visuals.
- Playing video games and visiting cinemas.

WORK PORTFOLIO

https://habibllahi.github.io/personal/portfolio.html